Shreehari Aramanadka: Software Engineer

+91 7795272860 - shreehari.aramanadka@gmail.com - linkedin - github - Bangalore, India

SUMMARY

With \sim **6 years** of industry experience in software development, I excel in crafting solutions for intricate technical challenges. Proficient in software design and development, I bring analytical prowess, effective communication, and mentorship skills to the table. As a dedicated software engineer, I am poised to contribute expertise and drive success in any project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, Golang. **Web Frameworks:** Django, Flask, FastAPI, Falcon, NodeJS.

Web Technologies: Html, CSS, JQuery, React.

Databases/Data Stores: Postgres, Mongodb, Mysql, Sqllite3, Elasticsearch, Redis, RabbitMq.

Tools and Cloud: Celery, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher, Newrelic, AWS, OpenCV, scrapy, nginx, Jira, Confluence.

Development Approaches: Test Driven Development, Domain Driven Development, CI/CD.

Project Management Approaches: Waterfall, Agile

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

YouGov, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

September 2020 - Present

Projects: Profiles Lite, Brandindex Lite, Codebook, Customer Profiles, Purchase Service

- Developing and maintaining **6 microservices** responsible for operating products to serve market research insights to customers.
- Architecting Codebook v2, slashing API response times from 3s to under 200ms for a faster user experience.
- Designing payment integration to the SaaS product using event sourcing approach.
- Improved performance of widget **fetching apis by 40**%. This involved migrating from polling to a pub-sub mechanism and analyzing performance using metrics collected in newrelic.
- Mentoring, guiding, pair programming, code reviewing with junior members to establish best engineering practices in the products.
- Improved code coverage in a legacy system from 70% to 95% by introducing hexagonal architecture, unittests, and integration tests.

Senior Software Developer

K12 Techno Services Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, Karnataka, India

October 2018 - September 2020

Projects: LetsEduvate ERP, QuestBox

- Improved performance of APIs in educational **ERP by 43**%, this involved introducing right indices at the database level, query optimization, and introducing caching mechanism.
- Designing and architecting multiplayer quiz to handle 20k parallel connections using websockets.
- Decoupled ERP applications into multiple submodules to increase maintainability, architecting permission models for granular access of features to different roles in the system.
- Establishing CI/CD for the ERP using gitlab runners deploying to aws infrastructure.
- Rapid integration of ZOOM APIs into ERP to run schools online when COVID happened.
- Lead a team of 4 backend engineers, mentoring juniors, conducting peer learning sessions, technology presentations, etc.

Analyst

Dell EMC, Bangalore, Karnataka, India

July 2018 - October 2018

Projects: SAP Basis Team

- Proposed and built a tool for checking production server's up/down status using Python
- Automation of report generation on server's status, using exported log files

EDUCATION

BMS Institute of Technology

Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

June 2014 - July 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

- Linkedin Learning Kubernetes: Microservices
- Udemy Complete Python Based Image Processing and Computer Vision